How are you?
Didn't we just talk about that?
That was yesterday.
Today is Tuesday.
So I've been here long?
A month.
Wayne Says
My grief pattern is atypical
Yeah
Got to talk with Wayne.
I think he gives too much medication
Way too much
Stop it, please.
trust on this to be smarter than you.
He strayed out of medical school
He don't know what he's doing
I've treated ten tenths
as many patients as he has
But you're not a doctor.
No, I'm not
And I'm proud that I'm not a doctor like him.
There is nothing...
atypical about your grief
It was my fault.
What about me?
I was there too.
I could have stopped him.
No.
You didn't know that he...
Started waking up lately
I was aware that he would sometimes...
wake up
And crawl out of bed
And walk about
Just as you thought that
he was soundly asleep
He could open the baby gate
He...
He woke up...
And w...
Was confused
Hey!
Dr. Wayne says he won't be back home.
You couldn't leave it, could you?
You had to mettle.
This place leads nowhere.
On the contrary...
Grief
It's not a disease...
It's a natural healthy reaction.
You can't just remove it
You mustn't...
Wayne knows you're a therapist
He said you shouldn't treat your own family
In principle I agree, but...
But you're just so much smarter
Aren't you?
I love you.
Nothing hurts more than
to see the one thy in love...
Subjected to mistakes and wrongs
No therapist can know
as much about you as I do
- It hurts.
- I know.
There's no way around it.
I want to talk to...
I'm not gonna let you do that.
Why not just go all alone?
No.
A little change.
Wouldn't get any worse...
Yes, it will.
You're always been distant from me and Nick
Ever I come to think of it
Very very distant
Okay
Can you give me some examples
from this?
Hell, That's not that difficult to understand.
I've lost someone, for instance...
You terribly distant lost someone
As a father...
And as a husband.
And that was Nick's last summer
you missed that on
Too bad
I never interested you.
Until now.
That I'm your patient.
Perhaps I'm not supposed
to talk about these things
There is nothing you can't talk about
You are indifferent
to whether your child is alive or dead
I bet you have a lot of
clever therapist replies to that.
Haven't you?
Well, actually...
It was to...
Honor your wish.
You wanted peace to write.
Perhaps I didn't mean it
What I understood...
Is that you want me to ride alone
That you and Nick,
were going to go to Eden.
Just the two of you
That way
you could finish your thesis
But I didn't
You didn't?
You see?
You didn't even know that.
Why did you give up?
That's not like you
The hope project Just seemed...
Less important upthere.
As you said,
When I like told you about my subject...
Glib
I never called your subject glib
Perhaps you didn't use that word,
but that's what you meant.
And all of a sudden
It was glib
Or even was...
some kind of lie.
I see
No, You don't see.
You see a lot of things
But not that.
Inhale...
On a count of five
Call me, call me.
Just... Follow me...
Do it with me... Inhale...
Inhale...
on a count to five...
Inhale... Two
Stay with me...
I'm Gonna teach you how to breathe.
Inhale...
2... 3...
4, 5, hold.
4, 5, exhale...
Good.
Imagine...
Imagine you're blowing on your...
Vessel plumbs
Calmly, quietly...
Yes, yes, that's good.
That's good.
That's very good.
I told you there would be a change.
You're still mourning
but you're in a new phase.
What phase?
Anxiety.
Yes
This is physical.
It's dangerous.
No, it's not dangerous.
Just as your grief wasn't dangerous
a main part of anxiety
Is physical
Dizzy spells
Dry mouth...
misguided hearing...
Trembling
Heavy breathing...
Less pulse...
Nausea...
Hey!
Easy...
Never screw your therapist.
No matter how much
your therapist may like it
I know that distracts you, but...
It's not good for us.
Do the breathing.
Hold
Exhale
You love me?
Yes, I do
Then help me.
It's what I'm doing
Exposure
That's the only thing that really works...
Everything else is...
Just talk
You have to have the courage
to stay in the situation that frightens you.
And then you'll learn
that fear isn't dangerous.
Let's make a list of things
you're afraid of.
In the top
You put the situation you fear the most
But I don't know
what I'm afraid of
Just... take your time.
I'm thinking.
Okay
I'm thinking, but...
Can't I just be afraid
without a definite object?
No, no!
This won't do
Stupe Stupidest thing I could do to you
If you can't tell me...
What your fear's of.
Maybe it would be easier for you to tell me
Where you're afraid?
Where would you feel most exposed?
What would be the worst place?
An apartment?
The street?
A store?
The park?
Listening to someone, maybe.
The woods.
The woods?
The woods, yes.
It's funny because...
you were the one that always wanted
to go into the woods
What scares you about the woods?
What frightens you... there?
Everything
Tell me what you think
is supposed to happen in the woods.
Eh?
Is it any woods in particular?
Eden.
Eden?
What do you say we put...
A garden round Eden
at the top of the pyramid?
No.
Not quite at the top.
Okay
It's... It's okay
- I'm sorry
- It's okay
We can start by working on your expectations
Close your eyes.
Feel the seat underneath you.
Feel yourself sinking down into it
Folding you...
It's a nice feeling.
What you feel is a pleasant warmth
and heaviness
your breath... is deep
I gather
You sink...
Down...
Imagine you're at Eden.
Imagine you arrived
at Eden through the woods.
Tell me what you see?
I'm at the bridge.
It's evening
Almost no voice can be heard.
The water is running without a sound.
Darkness comes out anytime here
I walk into it
The little deers... are hiding.
Among their friends. As usual.
Is it Difficult to go upthere?
No.
Not really.
That is almost okay
In a mountain of trees...
Almosty
There's a built foxhole
How do you feel there?
I can't really tell.
It should be easy...
passing
And yet...
It's like walking through mud.
The trunk is thick
the dear old ****
It has some strange kind of personality.
I've always found that.
No.
Where are you, are you...?
Are you heading for the cabin?
Yes, I am
I'm walking up above...
Through the tall grass...
Then don't come in.
Don't go in.
You see outside you're afraid of
Don't look around...
No.
Lie down on the green.
You want me to lie down?
Lie down on the grass.
On top of all the plants?
Yes, lie down on the plants.
Are you lying down?
Yes
Good
What is everything like around you?
Green.
It's all very green.
Good
Now will you do what I ask you?
Yes
What do you want me to do?
I want you...
To melt... into the green.
Don't fight it.
Just...
Turn green.
No matter what happens
you were there. You did it.
Let fear come, if it likes.
Remember.
But the mind can concieve
and believe it can achieve
What's wrong?
Ground is burning.
The ground is not burning.
Gotta go.
I want to lie down.
Just for a minute.
Sure.
Yea. We'll take a rest.
Shouldn't we go home?
Yeah
Yeah, we should.
Scared?
Stay awake for me.
Relax
Stay... stay in there.
It's just stupid acorns
What are you doing?
I'm just...
Setting up... a little exercise.
It's... It's like a...
It's like a game.
You cheated me yesterday.
Running is not good.
...You have to
really feel the grass.
I want you to go from this stone...
To this stone.
Pretty scary, huh?
You're ready?
Yea
I'll give you a ride.
I'll put you on the first stone.
Stay with me
Here we go
Put your foot down
I got you.
I got you
I'm right here.
I can't do this.
Yes, you can.
You can and you will.
Just like I will.
We're gonna walk together.
We're gonna walk together, okay?
Now...
Alright now, Breathe.
Let's step off the rock.
And step on that grass.
Step down
See?... What happened?
Keep breathing...
See? Keep breathing
I've got you
You're really doing great
Okay?... keep breathing.
Five, five and five.
You're almost there.
You're almost there
You're doing great
...Five.
We're there... We are there
Here, told you
You did it
You learned something.
Didn't you?
You did beautiful.
I miss him so much...
I've been afraid of here before.
Yes, it seems likely.
I just didn't know it was fear.
I became afraid
... and I stopped writing.
What was different... the last time?
I heard a sound.
Nick?
Nick!
You didn't hear Nick screaming.
Apparently not.
And because you experienced
something that you can't explain rationally,
You placed
Eden very high on the pyramid chart.
Eden was the catalyst
that triggered your fear.
You jumped to conclusions.
Entitled the emotional event with a place.
When you feel threat
It's natural to react.
If the danger were real...
Your fear would save your life.
Because your adrenaline will be used
for fight or flight.
But what you're experiencing
is panic, nothing more.
The scream wasn't real
Stop!
Calm down.
You shouldn't have come here.
You're just so damn arrogant.
But this may not last.
Have you thought of that?
Oak trees grow to be hundreds of years old
They only have to produce
one single tree, every hundred years.
In order to perpetuate...
May sound benign to you but...
It was a big thing for me to realize that
when I was out here with Nick.
The acorns fell on the roof then too...
Kept falling, and falling
And dying... and dying.
And I understood that...
Everything that used to be beautiful about Eden
Was perhaps hideous
Now I could hear
what I couldn't hear before.
The cry of... all the things that are to die
It's all...
very touching
If it was a children's book.
acorns don't cry
You know that as well as I do.
That's what fear is.
Your thoughts distort reality.
Look the other way around...
Satan's Church
Satan?... Jesus!
Nature is Satan's Church.
What?
Well, there you have him
That was his brother.
Nick?
He drifted away from me the last time.
He was always out and about...
He might have made more of an effort
to be there for me.
You look like you slept well.
Thanks, I did.
I just wanted to say how happy
I am that you're here...
I love you darling...
Did you have a good sleep?
I've just been having a lot of...
crazy dreams...
Dreams are of no interest
in modern psychology.
Freud is dead, isn't he?
What are you doing?
Look!
I'm well again.
I'm cured.
See? perfect.
I'm fine.
You can't just be happy for me, can you?
Chaos... reigns
Chapter Three: The despair
I want to do one more excercise.
It's like a role play.
My role...
Is..
All the thoughts
that provoke your fear...
Yours...
is rational thinking.
I am nature...
All the things that you call nature.
Okay Mr. Nature
what do you want?
To hurt you as much as I can.
How?
How do you think?
By Frightening me?
By killing you.
Nature can't hurt me.
You just told you're the green in the outside...
No, I'm more than that.
I don't understand.
I'm outside, but also...
within
I'm nature of all human beings
Oh, That kind of nature.
The kind of nature that...
Causes people do
the evil things against women
That's exactly who I am.
That kind of nature interested me a lot.
When I was uphere
That kind of nature
was the subject to my thesis...
But you shouldn't underestimate Eden.
What did Eden do?
I discovered somethng else
in my material than I expected.
If human nature is evil...
Then that goes as well...
That the nature...
of the women.
Female nature.
The nature of all the sisters.
Women do not
control their own bodies
Nature does.
I have it in writing in my books.
The literature you used
in your office search...
Was about evil things
committed against women.
But you read it as proof
of the evil of women?
You were supposed to be critical of those says
That was your thesis
Instead you're embracing it
Do you know what you're saying?
Forget it.
I do not know why I said it.
It can't work anymore now.
Hit me.
What?
Hit me so it hurts...
No.
Hit me, please.
No!
I can't stand it
I do not want to
I do not want to...
Then you don't love me.
Okay
Maybe I don't love you.
Yeah
Again...
Again.
This is too from nature's spell...
Could start a hail storm...
I'm not gonna continue this
if you don't listen to me.
Good... and evil.
Have nothing to do with therapy.
You know how many innocent women were
killed in the sixteenth century alone
just for being women?
I'm sure you do... Many.
Not because they were evil...
I know.
It's just sometimes I forget.
The evil you talk about is an obsession.
Obsessions never materialize.
It's a scientific fact.
Anxieties can't trick you into doing things
you won't do otherwise...
It's like hypnotizing you
You can't be hypnotized into doin
something you wouldn't...
Normally do.
Something against your nature.
You understand me?
Yeah, I think so.
You think so?
You don't have to understand me, just trust me.
What's this?
It's from the medical officer
It's a copy of the autopsy report.
The autopsy?
They performed an autopsy?
I didn't wanna tell you,
because you weren't feeling well.
Well
What did they find?
Nothing that would have any...
bearing on the case.
The only abnormality
in the victim is a slight deformity
of the bones in his feet,
of an earlier date
We did not attention a significance to this.
You were rather to put Nick's shoes on
wrong in this picture?
Well
How I would?!
A slip of the mind that day?
I wish
Herself.
Bastard.
You're leaving me, aren't you?
get off me, bastard.
You're leaving me.
I'm not.
I'm helping you.
- You're leaving me, aren't you?
- No!
- I love you.
- I don't believe you!
Yes
I don't believe you!
I don't fucking believe you!
Where are you?
You bastard!
How dare you leave me?
You said you wanted to help me.
Where are you?
You bastard!
Get out!
Get out! You bastard!
You bastard!
Get out!
Sorry.
You gotta get this thing off... my leg
I can't find the wrench.
Did you want to kill me?
Not yet
The three beggars aren't here yet.
The three beggars?
What does that mean?
When the three beggars arrive...
Someone must die.
I see.
The crying woman
is a scheming woman.
False in legs
False in thighs
False in breasts
Teeth, hair and eyes
Hold me
There is no such constellation.
None of it is any use
Not good.
No!